

Curriculum Vitae for Kent-Andre Mardal

Personal information

Address: Bestumveien 86P E-mail: kent@xal.no

0283 Oslo Phone: +4793610854

Born: 26.11.1974 Nationality: Norwegian

Summary

I am a Professor of Applied Mathematics, with a PhD from 2003. I have a broad background in programming, computational modeling, image analysis and fluid mechanics. I have educated more than 40 MSc students and 15 PhD students, written more than 100 scientific papers on topics ranging from theoretical mathematics to clinical applications, and am experienced in working with and leading multidisciplinary teams.

Technical skills

Frameworks FEniCS, Numpy, SciPy, FreeSurfer.

Languages Python, Matlab, C++.

Education

2003 Ph.D. in Scientific Computing, Department of Informatics, University

of Oslo. Thesis title 'Software tools and numerical methods for the

incompressible Navier-Stokes equations'

Professional experience

2019 –	Consulant for Expert Analytics (part time)
2015 –	Professor, Division of Mechanics, Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo
2014 –	Adjunkt Scientist (part time), Scientific Computing Department, Simula Research Laboratory.
2015 – 2014	Associate Professor, Division of Mechanics, Department of Mathematics, University of Oslo
2014 - 2007	Senior Scientific Resarcher, Simula Research Laboratory
2014 - 2007	Associate Professor (part time), University of Oslo
2007 - 2003	Postdoctoral Fellow at Simula Research Laboratory

expertanalytics.no

Languages

English Fluent Norwegian Fluent

Personal skills

Communication As a presenter, teacher, mentor and supervisor, I frequently present,

discuss, and educate technical consepts at various levels. Most of my research is interdisciplinary, frequently with experts with domain know-

ledge very different from my own.

Management I am currently managing two research projects finanzed by the Nor-

wegian Research Council "Alzheimer's physics" and Scientific Machine Learning" of 28 MNOK, in addition to participating as workpackage leader in other projects. Hence, I am experience in managment.

Some interests and hobbies

Academic Biomechanics, Scientific Computing, Numerics, Machine Learning

Other Reading, traveling, football, skiing.

Extended descriptions of selected projects

Activity Alzheimer's physics

Period 2020-2024

Role Principle Investigator

Staffing Funded by Norwegian Research Council (12 MNOK)

Description This project aims at developing numerical methods, biomechanical

models and software tools for simulating prevailing theories of the physics that underlies the developement of Alzheimer's disease. The project is interdisciplinary and involves clinicians as well as computa-

tional scientists, imaging experts.

Tools Python, HPC-computing, FEniCS, Machine Learning

Activity Scientific Machine Learning

Period 2019-2023

Role Principle Investigator

Staffing Funded by Norwegian Research Council (16 MNOK)

Description This project aims at developing robust methods where numerical met-

hods such as finite elements are combined with neural networks in a

compatible, stable way.

Tools Python, HPC-computing, FEniCS, Machine Learning

Activity Notably - Novel cascade technology for optimal utilization of animal

and marine by products

Period 2018-2021

Role Work-package leader

Staffing Funded by Norwegian Research Council (Work package: 2 MNOK)
Description Currently about 50% of chicken and fish are wasted in production. This

project aims at developing simulation tools for improving hydrolysis

and making proteins etc available for utilization in other products.

Tools Python, HPC-computing, FEniCS, Machine Learning